Speaker: The Glass Bottle. Part 1
Hassan and Walid are brothers.
They live in a small house in the desert, near the mountains, a long way from a town or village.
They’re very poor. They have no money and they have no animals.
Their house only has two rooms. Every day is the same.
They get up, and they have sweet black coffee for breakfast.
Then Hassan works in the fields –
but Walid just sits and looks at the hot, empty desert and the hot, empty sky.
They live with their mother. She takes care of them, but she’s old and tired.
One day she says, "We’re poor and hungry. Why don’t you leave here and find work?
We need money for food and clothes."
"If you want some money, you have your silver ring – you can sell that," answers Walid.
"I can’t sell it," she says. "It’s your father’s. Every night I look at it and remember him."
Hassan wants to help his mother, and he decides to leave home.
His mother gives him bread, and water in a glass bottle.
He kisses her, and he walks towards the mountains.